<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://docbook.org/xml/4.4/dtd/docbook.dtd" []>
<chapter>
  <title>Server Configuration</title>
  <section>
    <title>Setting Your Server</title>
    <para>The E-LMIS has been tested in a number of different linux settings.
            Most commonly, the E-LMIS has been deployed on the cloud Setting.
            Getting your server up and running in the cloud environment is fairly straight forward process.
            The following simple step by step process could be used to configure your linux server environment.
        </para>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Install Tomcat 7 or above</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Install Postgres 9 or above</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Download the war file from the following URL</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Deploy the war file and enjoy</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
    <note>
      <para>
                For best result with your configuration, we recommend that you configure your tomcat server behind an apache server.
                You could configure apache2 to communicate with the tomcat server using the AJP protocol.
            </para>
    </note>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Optimizing your server</title>
    <para>The following tips could be used to optimize the performance of your E-LMIS configuraiton.</para>
    <para>
                        Setup Apache to put an expires header on HTML, CSS and Javascript files.
                        This tells the Browser to use it&apos;s own cache for a majority of the static files in the application.
                        This setting reduces the size of files that have to be transported to the client machine every time a page is opened.
                    </para>
    <para>
                        Add a deflate header in your apache configuration for JSON files to be comressed using GZIP.
                    </para>
  </section>
</chapter>
