<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. -->
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://docbook.org/xml/4.4/dtd/docbook.dtd" []>
<chapter>
  <title>Report and Requisition</title>
  <para>
    Report and Requisitions are the core practice of any Pull Logistics system. In a pull supply chain, the movement of stock is driven by request and reporting submitted by the pulling logistics unit. In the E-LMIS, this logistics unit is the service delivery unit (the Health Facility).

    The E-LMIS is designed to be configurable for different countries and different program implementations. To Acheive this, the E-LMIS has features to configure the report and requision form. 
  </para>
  <note>
    <para>
      Report and Requsition is also known as "R&amp;R"
    </para>
  </note>
  <para>
            To configure the R&amp;R Template for a given program area, please go to Administration -&gt; Configure -&gt; R&amp;R Template
  </para>
  
  <figure>
    <title>R&amp;R Template Configuration</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata width="100%" fileref="../images/configure-rnr.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <para>
      From the screen that was displayed, please select a program that you would like to customize. 
  </para>
  <para>
    A program could be configured as a "pull logistics program" or a "push logistics" program. 
    The fundamental difference between these two types of programs is that pull program functions by the Service Delivery Unit (SDUs) sending a reqeust and requisition form. On the other hand, in a push program, SDUs are expected to be fulfilled by the Warehouses based on Formula's such as demographics based estimate instead of the requests from the service Delivery Units.
  </para>
  <note>
    <para>
      Only "pull" programs are displayed in the E-LMIS R&amp;R Template configuraiton page.
    </para> 
  </note>
  <figure>
    <title>R&amp;R Template Configuration Detail</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata width="100%" fileref="../images/configure-rnr-detail.png"/>
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <para>
    The R&amp;R Template Configuration detail page allows you to decide which columns are applicable for a specific program. You can also use this page to decide on and arrange the order of the Report and Requisition columns. 
  </para>
</chapter>
